They just messed with the wrong Mexican.
Machete is a action, comedy, thriller film directed by Robert Rodriguez.
After being set-up and betrayed by the man who hired him to assassinate a Texas Senator, an
ex-Federale launches a brutal rampage of revenge against his former boss.
Machete, played by Danny Trejo.
Luz, played by Michelle Rodriguez.
Sartana Rivera, played by Jessica Alba.
Senator John McLaughlin, played by Robert De Niro.
Rogelio Torrez, played by Steven Seagal.
Padre Cortez, played by Cheech Marin.
Machete (also known as Robert Rodriguez's Machete) is a 2010 American
exploitation action film directed by Robert Rodriguez and Ethan Maniquis.
The film is an expansion of a fake trailer published as a part of the promotion of
Rodriguez's and Quentin Tarantino's 2007 Grindhouse double-feature.
Machete continues the B movie and exploitation style of Grindhouse.
The film stars Danny Trejo as the title character,
reprising the role from the fake trailer.
Trejo also previously portrayed an alternate version of
the character in the Spy Kids films.
The film additionally co-stars Steven Seagal, Michelle Rodriguez, Jessica Alba,
Lindsay Lohan, Cheech Marin, Don Johnson and Robert De Niro.
It is Trejo's first lead role as the character, and Seagal's first theatrically released film
since 2002's Half Past Dead (and his last theatrically released film to date).
Machete was released in the United States by 20th
Century Fox on September 3, 2010.
A sequel, Machete Kills, solely directed by
Rodriguez, was released on October 11, 2013.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one, illegal
immigration, border patrol, immigration law, machete.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.